ｱｺﾞが ｹﾂみたいで
かっこいいってお客さんだって➡
隣には金時がいて｡
好きで
ｹﾂｱｺﾞになったんじゃないのに！
ｹﾂｱｺﾞ いいじゃありませんか！
(神楽)新八｡
(新八)夢を見ていましたよ｡
夢？
ﾎﾝﾄになりたかった｡
ええ｡ 幸せな夢です｡
ｹﾂｱｺﾞのどこが悪いんですか！
そんな 幸せな夢です｡
ｵﾚがかぶき町で
ﾅﾝﾊﾞｰﾜﾝﾎｽﾄになって➡
そして 店のｵｰﾅｰは神楽さんで｡
なりたかったな｡ ﾅﾝﾊﾞｰﾜﾝﾎｽﾄ｡
[New TV Show]
いるかも
しれないじゃないですか！
[Kin Tama]
もうやめて！
[Episode 3]
Shinpachi...
みんなｱｺﾞがｹﾂみたいになればいい｡
I was dreaming...
＜ すべての望みを絶たれ
かぶき町に雨が降る｡
Dreaming?
Yes... It was a happy dream...
ｵﾚたちは もがく力も失って➡
I was working in Kabukicho...
I became the number one host...
ただ
空を恨むことしかできなかった＞
and Kintoki was next to me...
And the owner of the place was Kagura-san...
Such a happy dream...
I wanted to become the number one host...
So badly...
I didn't choose to end up with this buttchin!
What's so bad about having a buttchin?!
There isn't anything wrong with a buttchin!
There might be customers who find a buttchin attractive, who knows!
Just stop!
Everybody should end up with butt-like chins.
All hope was lost as rain fell upon Kabukicho.
We lost our will to fight
and could only curse at the sky.
[To Be Continued with the Final Episode!!]
眠れないｱﾙ｡
I can't sleep.
I can't sleep at all.
全然 眠れないｱﾙ｡
毛ほども眠くないｱﾙ｡
Can't sleep a wink.
寝よう寝ようと思うほど
頭が冴えていくね｡
The harder I try to fall asleep,
the more awake I feel.
全然 眠くないｱﾙ｡
I don't feel like sleeping at all.
["Sleep Helps a Child Grow"]
(ﾉｯｸ)
What?
(銀時)なに？
眠れないｱﾙ｡
I can't sleep.
あっそ｡ 夜更かしもほどほどにな｡
Oh, really...
Don't stay up too late.
明日 仕事あんだから｡
We have work tomorrow.
(ﾉｯｸ)
何だよ｡
What is it?
眠れないｱﾙ｡
それさっき聞いた！
I can't sleep.
You already said that.
眠れないなら眠くなるまで
寝なきゃいいだろ｡
If you can't fall asleep, stay up until you're sleepy.
You're so annoying.
うるせえな｡
(ﾉｯｸ)
Let me sleep, okay?
頼むから寝かせてくれよ｡
I said we have work...
仕事あるっつって…｡
眠れないｱﾘｭｰ｡
I can't sleep.
Hey! What are you doing?!
って おい！ 何してんだﾃﾒｴ！
I can't sleep a wink at all.
全然 まったく
まんじりとも 眠れないｱﾘｭｰ｡
Like I care!
知らねえよ！
嫌がらせしてんじゃねえよ！
Stop bugging me!
I can't sleep...
眠れない｡
寝かせろよ 私を｡
Put me to sleep.
あっ？
お前の持てる力すべてで➡
Use everything in your power to put me to sleep.
私を眠らせてみろよ｡
勝手に寝ろよ！
Just go to sleep by yourself!
それが人にものを頼む態度か！
Is that how you ask somebody for a favor?!
Man...
ったく つきあってられっかよ！
I can't put up with this.
その布団
寝やすそうｱﾙな｡ 代われよ｡
That futon looks more comfortable to sleep on.
Switch with me.
えっ？
私がそれで寝るから｡
I'm gonna sleep there.
お前は押し入れで寝ろ｡
You sleep in the closet.
いちゃもんつけてんじゃねえよ
布団なんて どれも同じだろうが｡
Don't be so picky.
All futons are the same!
あんな狭いところで
ｵﾚが寝られるか｡
How am I supposed to sleep in that small space?!
いいからどけよ｡
うわぁ～！
Just move outta the way.
あ～ なんか寝られる気がするね｡
Ah, I think I can fall asleep like this.
これだったら いける気がする｡
This futon might put me to sleep.
永遠に眠り続けろ ｸｿｶﾞｷ｡
Never wake up again, stupid brat.
ったくよ なんだってんだ
せっかく寝てたのによ｡
Man...
What is this...
I'd managed to fall asleep.
ｵﾚ ひゃっこい布団やなんだよ｡
I don't wanna sleep on a cold futon.
眠れないｱﾙ｡
結局 同じかよ！
I can't sleep.
So nothing changed?!
やっぱし 全然ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙ
全然眠くならないね｡
This is no use.
I don't feel sleepy at all.
枕が おっさん臭くて
全然眠れなくなってきたｱﾙ｡
I can't fall asleep 'cause the pillow smells like an old man.
ｵﾒｴが代われって
言ったんだろうが！
You're the one who told me to switch with you!
That futon looks more comfortable to sleep on.
そっちの布団 寝やすそうｱﾙな｡
Switch with me.
代われよ こっちと｡
ｷﾘねえっつの！
This will never end!
なんか全然眠れないから➡
I can't fall asleep
どうやったら眠れるか
いろいろ考えてたｱﾙ｡
so I've been thinking of ways to fall asleep.
そしたら だんだん
今までどうやって寝てたのか➡
And now, I'm no longer sure how I used to fall asleep.
わからなくなってきたｱﾙ｡
寝方を忘れてしまったｱﾙ｡
I've forgotten how to fall asleep.
どうやったら眠れるｱﾙ｡
How do I fall asleep?
どうやったら眠りのなかに
入っていけるｱﾙ｡
How do I make my way into slumberland?
とりあえず黙れ そして
目をつぶって じっとしてろ｡
Start by shutting up!
Then close your eyes and stay still!
いつの間にか寝てるから｡
You'll eventually fall asleep.
But Gin-chan, when you stop and think about it,
だって 銀ちゃん
よくよく考えるｱﾙ｡
寝るって いったい何ｱﾙか｡
what is sleep?
目つぶっても
結局 私たち瞼閉じてるだけで➡
When we close our eyes, we're just shutting our eyelids.
眼球は 中でｺﾞﾛｺﾞﾛしてるｱﾙ｡
Our eyeballs are still darting around.
真っ暗だけど 結局
それは 瞼の裏側見てるだけで➡
It's completely dark, but that's because we're looking at the inside of our eyelids.
眠ってるわけじゃないｱﾙ｡
It doesn't mean we're asleep.
その証拠に 昼間
日向で目を閉じると真っ赤ｱﾙ｡
To prove it, if you close your eyes during the day, it's completely red.
眼球どうすれば眠れるｱﾙか｡
What do I do with my eyeballs if I want to fall asleep?
まっすぐ瞼の裏
見てればいいｱﾙか｡
Should I just stare at the inside of my eyelids?
それとも
上のほう見てればいいｱﾙか｡
Or should I look up?
どうすれば眼球は…｡
やめろよ～！
What do I do to-
Cut it out!
こっちまで
眠れなくなってきたろうが！
Now I can't fall asleep!
どうしてくれんだよ
意識してたら ｵﾚも➡
What are you going to do about this?!
Now that you got me thinking about it, I can't fall asleep either!
訳わかんなくなってきちゃった
じゃねえか！
上のほうだっけ？
下のほうだっけ？
Did I look up? Did I look down?
眼球の置き場がわかんねえよ！
I don't know what to do with my eyeballs!
あと 寝るときって
息 口でするんだっけ？
And do we breathe with our mouths when we sleep?
鼻でするんだっけ？ 口から吸って
鼻から出すんだっけ？
Or with our noses?
Or do we breathe in through our mouths and out through our noses?
鼻から吸って 口からだっけ？
やめろ！
Or do we breathe in through our noses and out through our mouths?
Cut it out!
手って
組んだほうがいいんだっけ？
Should I cross my arms?
横に置くんだっけ？
布団から出すんだっけ？
Should I leave them at my sides?
Outside the covers?
しまうんだっけ？
枕の位置って どのへんだっけ？
Inside the covers?
How should the pillow be placed?
仰向けだっけ？ うつ伏せだっけ？
やめろ！
Face-up?
Face-down?
Cut it out!
人って どこから産まれて
どこに向かっていくんだっけ？
Where do we come from? Where are we going?
宇宙の向こう側って
どんなになってるんだっけ？
What's beyond the edge of the universe?
ｱﾆﾒは なんで
儲からないんだっけ？
やめろよ！
Why doesn't anime make lots of money?
Cut it out!
うわぁ～ 眠れねえ！
I can't sleep!
もう全然眠れる気がしねえ！
I don't feel like sleeping at all!
Was it this hard to fall asleep?!
眠るのって
こんなに難しかったっけ？
ｵﾚたち 今まで こんな高度なこと
毎日やってたっけ？
Did we go through such an ordeal every night?!
眠るって何だっけ？
うるさい！
What is sleep again?
Shut up!
そんなややこしいこと考えてて
眠れるわけねえだろ！
You'll never fall asleep if you make everything so complicated!
どんだけ不器用なんだよ｡
How much of a failure are you?!
高倉健でも
もう少し うまいことやるわ！
Even Ken Takakura could do a better job!
[Note: Actor Ken Takakura is known for the phrase, "I'm a failure."]
I feel more and more awake.
どんどん頭が冴えていくｱﾙ
どうしたらいいね？
What do I do?
このままじゃ
私 一生眠れないね｡
At this rate, I'll never fall asleep for rest of my life.
Give me a break.
勘弁してくれよ
明日 仕事だって言ってんだろ｡
Didn't I tell you that we have work tomorrow?
もう夜中の２時半だぞ｡
It's 2:30 in the morning.
明日７時起きだ｡
We have to wake up at 7:00 tomorrow.
もう４時間半しか眠れねえよ｡
We only have four and a half hours to sleep.
ﾅﾎﾟﾚｵﾝでも
寝起き愚痴ってくるよ｡
That'd even make Napoleon bitch when he woke up.
我が輩の辞書には
睡眠３時間って書いてあるけど➡
"My dictionary says I only sleep for three hours but read between the lines!"
[Note: Napoleon is known for only sleeping three hours a day. He is also known for the quote "The word impossible is not in my dictionary."]
空気読め！ とか言ってくるよ｡
どうすればいいね？
先に寝ないでよ銀ちゃん｡
What should I do?
Don't fall asleep before me, Gin-chan.
とりあえず その
ｺﾞﾁｬｺﾞﾁｬものを考えるのをやめろ｡
For now, stop thinking about that stuff.
頭を使うな！
Don't use your head.
あのな そもそも睡眠なんてな➡
Okay?
Sleep isn't supposed to be something you can consciously force.
意識してとるもんじゃ
ねえんだよ｡
Humans who live regular lives will naturally fall asleep at night.
人間 規則正しく生活してりゃ➡
夜には
しぜんに眠れるもんなんだ｡
１日 汗水垂らして
一生懸命 働いて➡
If you work your sweaty ass off for a whole day,
心地よい疲れとともに眠る｡
you'll be so tired you can comfortably fall asleep.
これが
正しい睡眠というものなんだよ｡
That's how sleep is supposed to work.
そうか…｡
I see...
日がな１日じゅう ｺﾞﾛｺﾞﾛしてたのに
眠たくなるわけなんてないね｡
I can't fall asleep because I was lying around the whole day.
そうだろう？
お前が おかしいのは➡
Right?
The problem is with your lifestyle, not with your sleeping style.
["Don't just lay there! Help me clean up the house!"]
眠り方なんかじゃなくて
眠る前の生活のほうなんだよ｡
お前に言われたくないね｡
You're one to talk.
だったら さっさと
町内 ぐるっと走ってこい｡
If you understand, go run a lap around town.
お前に足りないのは適度な疲れだ｡
What you lack is fatigue.
わかったｱﾙ｡ ちょっと
ひとっ走り いってくるね｡
I got it.
I'm going off for a run.
銀ちゃん 先に寝たらﾀﾞﾒだよ｡
ちゃんと起きててね｡
Gin-chan, you can't fall asleep before me.
You'd better stay up.
Gin-chan...
銀ちゃん…
銀ちゃんてば…｡
Hey, Gin-chan...
ﾌｩ… ﾌｩ… 全然 眠れないｱﾙ｡
I can't fall asleep.
走ってきたのは いいけど➡
I did the running...
But now...
今度は 熱くて眠れないｱﾙ｡
ｺﾞﾎｯ ｺﾞﾎｯ ｺﾞﾎｯ…｡
I'm so hot...
I can't fall asleep.
誰が そんな虫の息になるまで
走ってこいって言ったよ!?
Who told you to run as hard as you can?!
眠れるわけねえだろ！
そんなﾍﾞﾀﾍﾞﾀの体で!!
Of course you can't fall asleep when you're all sweaty like that!
できるだけ疲れたほうが
すぐ眠れると思って➡
I figured I'd fall asleep faster if I was more tired,
町内50周してきたｱﾙ｡
so I ran fifty laps around town.
眠るどころか すべての細胞が
活性化してるのを感じる…｡
Sleep is out of the question now.
It feels like all my cells have activated.
感じるじゃねえよ！ 脳細胞は
著しく死滅していってるだろ！
Feels like it?
Your brain cells are dying!
さんざん 体 動かして➡
You can't fall asleep right after exercising so hard!
急に眠るなんて
できるわけねえだろ!!
いったん 風呂でも入って
汗 流して さっぱりしてこいよ｡
Go take a bath and cool yourself off!
ｵﾚの布団も ﾍﾞﾀﾍﾞﾀに
なっちまうだろうが!!
You've gotten my futon all sweaty now!
いやｱﾙ｡ 私に そんなﾋﾏないね｡
No.
I don't have time for that.
一刻も早く
眠らなければいけないね｡
I have to fall asleep as soon as possible.
(お腹の鳴る音)
どんだけ忙しいﾔﾂなんだよ｡
You're a busy person, huh?
眠りたいっつったり
腹減ったっていったり➡
First you want to sleep.
Now you're hungry.
羨ましいよ！ 楽しそうですね｡
いっぱいやりたいことがあって！
I envy you!
It must be fun to have so many things to do!
お腹じゃないもん｡ 屁だもん｡
That isn't my stomach. I'm farting.
屁でも腹でも どっちでもいいから
ちょっと静かにしてくれない？
I don't care what it is! Can you be quiet?!
どんだけ鳴ってんだよ｡
How long is that going to continue?!
ﾊｧ… うるさくて眠れやしねえ｡
It's so noisy I can't fall asleep.
わかった｡ じゃあ ｵﾚが
ﾒｼ 炊いといてやっから➡
Fine.
I'll go make you something to eat.
その間に お前
風呂 入ってこいや｡
You go take a bath during that time.
ﾒｼ！
Food?!
Everybody feels like sleeping after a meal, right?
ﾒｼ食ったあとは
誰でも眠くなるだろ｡
It's not very healthy, but that's a sacrifice you'll have to make.
本当は あんま体によくねえが
背に腹は かえられん｡
このままじゃ ｵﾚも眠れねえしな｡
At this rate, I won't be getting any sleep either.
銀ちゃん!!
Gin-chan!
Man, you stink!
臭っ… 寄るな｡ 早く入ってこい｡
Stay away! Go take a bath!
うん！ ありがとう 銀ちゃん！
Thanks, Gin-chan!
銀ちゃん…
銀ちゃんてば…｡
Gin-chan...
Hey, Gin-chan...
ﾌｩ… ﾌｩ… ﾌｩ… ﾋｨ ﾋｨ ﾌｩ…｡
[Note: Kagura is using the Lamaze method of breathing for expectant mothers.]
何してる？
What are you doing?
全然 眠れないｱﾙ｡ ﾋｨ… ﾌｩ…｡
I don't feel like sleeping at all.
風呂 入ったのに… ﾌｩ… ﾌｩ…
寝苦しくて全然ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙ… ﾌｩ… ﾌｩ…｡
I took a bath,
but I'm having trouble breathing so I can't fall asleep!
誰が 腹式呼吸するまで
食べてこいって言ったよ!?
Who told you to eat so much that you'd start breathing with your diaphragm?!
眠れるわけねえだろ そんな腹で！
Of course you can't fall asleep when your stomach's that full!
だって… いっぱい
ご飯 炊いてあったから…｡
But...
You made all that food...
明日の朝の分も入ってたんだよ！
The rest of that was for breakfast!
なに ｵﾚの分まで食ってんだ
ｸｿｶﾞｷ!!
Why did you eat my share, stupid brat?!
ﾀﾞﾒｱﾙ… 苦しくて
寝返りも うてないね…｡
It's no use...
I'm in so much pain I can't even turn over...
もう一度 ｼｪｲﾌﾟｱｯﾌﾟ乱してくるｱﾙ…
ﾗﾝだけに…｡
I'll go run myself into shape...
[Note: "Shape Up Ran" was a JUMP manga from the 80s.]
By taking a run.
誰が うまいこと
言えって言ったよ！
Who told you to be witty?!
やめろよ！
また振り出しに戻るだろうが!!
Cut it out!
That'll just put us back where we started!
あ～あ… もう わかった｡
お前 明日 仕事休め｡
Ah...
Fine.
You don't have to work tomorrow.
ｵﾚと 新八だけで行ってくるから｡
Shinpachi and I can handle it.
だから ﾑﾘして寝なくていいから｡
So don't force yourself to sleep.
Just let me sleep, okay?
頼むから ｵﾚを寝させてくれ｡
No!
ｲﾔｱﾙ！
夜更かしは 美容の大敵ね！
Staying up late is bad for my skin!
そんな腹してるﾔﾂに
美容うんぬん言われたかねえよ！
Someone whose stomach is sticking all the way out shouldn't be talking about skin care!
おい 頼むよ もう４時だよ｡
Come on.
It's already 4:00.
明日７時起きだよ｡
３時間って…｡
I have to wake up at 7:00 tomorrow.
That's in three hours.
ﾅﾎﾟﾚｵﾝ もう朝 お母さんに
八つ当たりしまくりだよ｡
That'd even make Napoleon bitch at his mom in the morning!
He'd probably whine about the quality of the miso soup!
もう きっと 味噌汁の具に
ｹﾁつけてくるよ｡
"The word eggplant is not in my dictionary."
我が輩の辞書に ﾅｽはないとか
絡んでくるよ！
はあ…｡
わかったｱﾙ もう騒がないよ｡
Fine.
I'll stop making a fuss.
I won't bother you anymore.
銀ちゃんには
もう迷惑かけないね｡
You already fed me.
ご飯食べさせてくれたし｡
ああ｡
But if it's too quiet, I start thinking about stuff.
でも あんまり静かだと
いろいろ考えちゃうから➡
Can I turn on the radio?
ﾗｼﾞｵとか つけといていいｱﾙか？
If you keep the volume down.
音 小さめならな｡
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]ﾔﾝｸﾞﾅｲﾄﾄﾚｲﾝ！
Young Night Train!
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]ということで
早速いきましょうか！
So let's get started!
This is DJ Junnijiro, who just had a kidney stone removed,
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]こないだ腎臓結石が
治ったばかりの➡
ＤＪ純二郎がお送りする
３分で泣ける話｡
with stories that make you cry within three minutes!
Young Night Train!
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]ということで
早速いきましょうか！
So let's get started!
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]ＤＪ純二郎がお送りする
３分で泣ける話｡
This is DJ Junnijiro with stories that make you cry within three minutes!
[ﾗｼﾞｵ]最初のおたより 紹介します｡
ﾗｼﾞｵﾈｰﾑ ﾄﾑさんのおたよりですね｡
Allow me to introduce the first letter.
This letter is from Radio Name Tom.
"Sorry, Jerry."
[Note: From Tom and Jerry.]
＜ﾄﾑ:私に
初めて友だちができたのは➡
I will never forget about the first friend I ever had.
忘れもしない 10年前の夏でした＞
It happened during summer ten years ago.
I was a shy and quiet child who always played by myself.
＜引っ込み思案で いつもﾎﾟﾂﾝと
一人で遊んでいた私を気遣い➡
父が 連れてきてくれた友だち
それが ｼﾞｪﾘｰだった＞
So my father brought me a friend.
That was Jerry.
＜私と ｼﾞｪﾘｰは いつも一緒
どこへ行くにも一緒｡
Jerry and I were always together.
We went everywhere together.
何をするにも一緒｡
We did everything together.
まるで
本当の友だちのようだった｡
Just like real friends.
いろんな芸も教えた＞
I taught him many tricks.
待て｡
Wait!
Jerry's best trick was to wait.
＜ｼﾞｪﾘｰの十八番は 待て｡
どんなごちそうを前にしても➡
He would wait as long as I told him,
even when a feast was placed before him.
ひとたび待てと言えば
ｼﾞｪﾘｰは いつまでも待っていた｡
ｼﾞｪﾘｰ以外に
友だちなんていらない｡
I didn't need any friends besides Jerry.
That's how I felt at the time.
当時 そんなことを思っていた
私だったが➡
そんな思いとは裏腹に➡
But on the other hand,
an increasing number of children showed up who were interested in Jerry.
ｼﾞｪﾘｰに興味を持った子供たちが
私のまわりに増えはじめ➡
The next thing I knew, I'd made lots of friends besides Jerry.
いつの間にか 私には➡
ｼﾞｪﾘｰ以外の友だちが
たくさんできていた＞
待て｡
Wait.
＜それから 私の興味が
ｼﾞｪﾘｰから 他に移るのに➡
It didn't take very long for my interest to shift from Jerry to other things.
そう時間はかからなかった｡
以前のように私と一緒に
遊びに行きたがる ｼﾞｪﾘｰ｡
Jerry longed to play with me the way we used to.
ﾜﾝﾜﾝと吠えるｼﾞｪﾘｰ｡
Jerry would bark at me.
そんなときは
彼の十八番が役に立った｡
That was when his best trick would come in handy.
私は ｼﾞｪﾘｰにひと言 待て｡
I would say one word to Jerry.
"Wait."
ｼﾞｪﾘｰは いつも
私が帰ってくるまで➡
Jerry would always wait there for my return.
そこで待っていた｡
一歩も動かず｡
Without moving an inch.
He just waited for me to return.
ただ じっと
私の帰りを待っていた＞
By chance, my father's store went out of business,
＜そんな折 父の店が倒産し
裕福だった私の家は 没落｡
and my affluent family fell to ruin.
私たちは 借金取りに追われ
着の身着のままに➡
Chased by debtors,
we were forced to escape with only the clothes on our backs.
逃げ出すはめになった｡
自分たちの生活も
ままならない状況のなか➡
Though I was only a child,
I was still able to understand what must be abandoned in that situation.
真っ先に切り捨てるべき対象は
子供の私にも理解できた｡
自分の運命を察したのか➡
Perhaps he realized his own fate.
Jerry chased after me without pause.
ｼﾞｪﾘｰは 手足がちぎれんばかりに
追いすがってきた＞
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ… ｸｳ｡
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ… ｸｳ ｸｳ｡
Wait!
待て！
I delivered the usual word in a cold voice.
＜私は いつものひと言を
冷徹にあびせた｡
｢待て｣｡
Wait.
私は 一度も振り返ることなく
ｼﾞｪﾘｰの前を去った＞
I left Jerry behind without ever looking back.
A few months later, I returned to that spot.
＜それから数か月｡
私の足は
あの場所へと向かっていた｡
I had already moved to a faraway city,
すでに遠い町へ
引っ越していた私だったが➡
but I couldn't stop thinking about Jerry.
どうしてもｼﾞｪﾘｰのことが
頭から離れなかった｡
ｼﾞｪﾘｰなら きっと大丈夫｡
Jerry had to be fine.
Somebody must have taken him in.
きっと誰かが
拾ってくれているはず！
In retrospect, I probably wanted peace of mind.
今思えば
私は早く安心したかったのだ｡
I wanted to see Jerry alive as soon as I could,
私に罪はないことを｡
ｼﾞｪﾘｰが生きてる姿を見ることで➡
so I wouldn't have to feel guilty.
それを 早く確認したかったのだ＞
Jerry hadn't become someone else's pet or a rotting corpse.
＜ｼﾞｪﾘｰは 誰かのものにも
亡骸にもなっていなかった｡
Jerry was waiting as always.
ｼﾞｪﾘｰは いつものように
そこで待っていた｡
Without moving a step.
一歩も動かずに ただ じっと
私の帰りを待っていた＞
Waiting for my return.
あっ！
ﾋﾄﾞｲもんじゃろ｡
Sad, isn't it?
He was abandoned there a while back.
しばらく前に
そこに捨てられておってのう｡
親切な人が
連れていこうとしたり➡
Kind people would try to take him with them,
ｴｻをやろうとしたり
いろいろしとったんだが➡
or feed him or the like.
ｺﾔﾂ どういうわけか頑として
ここから一歩も動かなくってな｡
But this boy refused to budge at all.
In time, people stopped paying attention to him.
そのうち誰も相手に
しなくなってしもうた｡
He couldn't have expected his owner to return.
まさか 主人が戻ってくるとでも
思って➡
待っておったのかのう｡
Either way, it's a sad story.
いずれにしても 哀れな話じゃ｡
＜そっと手を伸ばし
頭をなでると➡
I reached out to softly pat his head,
かすかに開いた
うつろな目で私を見る｡
and his eyelids slowly parted to look up at me.
ｼﾞｪﾘｰは わずかに
ｼｯﾎﾟを振る素振りを見せると➡
Jerry's tail wagged ever so slightly.
それきり 動かなくなった…＞
And then, he never moved again.
(泣き声)
Little lady...
お嬢ちゃん そうか｡
ｱﾝﾀがｺｲﾂのご主人じゃったか｡
I see, you were his owner.
ｼﾞｪﾘｰは 私が帰ってくるのを
待ってたのね｡
Jerry was waiting for me to come back!
Waiting the whole time...
あのときから ずっと ずっと｡
The whole time...
ｼﾞｪﾘｰ！
Jerry!
私は あなたに
何て謝ればいいの!?
How can I apologize to you?!
何度 謝ればいいの!?
How many times do I need to apologize to you?!
あなたは私に
たくさんのものをくれた｡
You gave me so much!
ひとりぼっちの私の
寂しさを忘れさせてくれた｡
You taught me how to shed my loneliness when I was all alone!
You opened up the world to me!
世界を広げてくれた｡
You were my first friend!
初めての友達になってくれた｡
なのに… 私は！
私は あなたに！
And yet...
I...
I did...
I did such a terrible thing to my precious friend!
大切な友達に
なんてことを！
(泣き声)
There's no need to apologize.
詫びることなどないさ｡
こやつは ずっとｱﾝﾀを待っていた｡
He was always waiting for you.
そして ｱﾝﾀは ここに来た｡
それ以上に何がいる？
And you came.
What else did he need?
最後に主に会えて
こやつも幸せだったじゃろう｡
He must have been happy to meet his owner in the end.
そんなことない！
きっと恨んでるわ！
That's not true! He must hate me!
Because I was the one who caused Jerry's death!
だって ｼﾞｪﾘｰを死なせたのは
他でもない この私だもの！
Jerry isn't dead.
ｼﾞｪﾘｰは 死んでなどおらん｡
ちゃんと生きとるよ｡
He's still alive.
Where?!
どこに!?
どこにいるっていうのよ！
Where is he?!
Of course...
それは もちろん…｡
Right behind you!
お前の後ろにだぁ～!!
あぁ～!!
ﾊｧﾊｧ… ﾊｧﾊｧ… 何じゃ こりゃ!?
What is this?
What kind of story is this?
なんつう話だ！
いい話が なんで最終的に➡
Why did a touching story turn into a scary story at the end?!
怪談になってんだよ！
どこが泣ける話なんだよ！
How would this make people cry?!
泣き叫ぶ話じゃねぇか！
More like cry out in terror!
I can't sleep after hearing such a crazy story!
眠れるわけねえだろ！
こんなｲｶれた話 聞きながら！
The station must be getting barraged by complaints right now!
今頃 局に
ﾊﾞﾝﾊﾞﾝ苦情の電話かかってるよ！
That really caught me off guard.
あぁ ﾋﾞｯｸﾘした！
Not that I was scared or anything.
いやぁ 別にﾋﾞﾋﾞってねえけど➡
Hey, Kagura!
おい 神楽！ ﾗｼﾞｵも もうなしだ！
聞いてらんねえ こんな…｡
No more radio!
I can't listen to this...
(寝息)
H-Huh? She fell asleep.
あ… あれ？ 寝たんだ｡
R-Really...
そ… そうか｡
ようやく寝やがったか｡
She finally fell asleep?
はた迷惑なﾔﾛｳだ｡
Way to cause so much trouble.
やぁ よかった よかった｡
That's a relief...
これで 心置きなく
眠れるってもんだよ｡
Now I can sleep in peace.
Then I'll go to sleep, too.
じゃあ ｵﾚも寝よっかな｡ うん｡
Right behind you!
お前の後ろにだぁ～!!
はっ!?
な… な～んてね｡
Y-Yeah, right...
ﾌｯ… そんなさぁ さすがにｵﾚも➡
Y'know...
That crazy story isn't enough to scare me.
あんなﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬな怪談では
ﾋﾞﾋﾞんねえよ｡
ちょっと ﾋﾞｯｸﾘしたけど
あんなもん ｷﾞｬｸﾞだよ｡
Though it surprised me a bit.
That was just a comedy.
There isn't much of a difference between horror and comedy.
ﾎﾗｰとｷﾞｬｸﾞは 紙一重だからね！
今回は 全然…｡
This was totally...
Right behind you!
お前の後ろにだぁ～!!
C-Crap...
や… やべぇな｡
睡眠不足で なんか幻聴が…｡
I'm starting to hear things 'cause I didn't get enough sleep.
Hey, now I can't fall asleep...?
おい なんか 今度は
ｵﾚが 眠れなくなってきた…？
(咳払い)
Ah. Sorry if I woke you up, Kagura.
あっ ごめん
神楽 起こしちゃったら…｡
Looks like I'm sick.
ちょっと 風邪気味みたいで…｡
ﾌﾞﾊｯ ｺﾞﾎｺﾞﾎｯ！ ｳｴｪｰ！
K-Kagura-chan. You're actually awake, right?
か… 神楽ちゃん
起きてんだろ？ ﾎﾝﾄは｡
You were wide awake just a second ago.
さっきまで あ～んな
お目めﾊﾟｯﾁﾘだったろうが！
冗談きついぜ ﾎﾝﾄに もう…｡
This isn't funny, seriously.
ﾌﾌﾌﾌ… ﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
神楽ちゃん？ ねぇ 聞いてる？
Kagura-chan?
Hey, are you listening?
起きてるよね？
起きてるんだよねぇ？
You're awake, right?
Awake, right?
(寝息)
Wake up!
起きろ！
ﾃﾒｴ ふざけんじゃねえぞ！
Don't mess with me!
ｵﾚが ﾃﾒｴを寝かすために➡
How much effort do you think I spent to put you to sleep?!
どれだけしてやったと
思ってんだ!?
You just abandon me the second you're done?!
用が済んだら ﾎﾟｲ捨てか
このﾔﾛｳ お前！
You could at least talk with me a bit!
ちょっとくらい おしゃべりに
つきあってくれても➡
いいだろうが！ 小便くらい
You could at least come with me when I go to take a piss!
いいだろうが！
このﾔﾛｳ まだ狸寝入り➡
Are you going to keep pretending to sleep?
決め込むつもりか！
たたき起こして…｡
I'll beat you awake...
うわぁ!? ぐおっ！ ぶへっ！
(蹴る音)
よし その調子だ｡
もっとこい ｵﾗ！ 死ぬ気でこい！
Okay, that's good.
Bring it on!
Like you're ready to die!
If you're gonna hit me, you had better knock me out!
殴るなら
気絶させるくらい殴れよ！
No, really...
つぅか お願い！
気絶させてくれ！
Please knock me out!
誰かぁ～ ｵﾚを眠らせてくれ～!!
Somebody put me to sleep!
Kyu-chan, happy **th birthday.
The next episode...
"That Person Looks Different From Usual During A Birthday Party."
[Tojo gathered everyone together to throw a surprise birthday party for Kyubei.]
[The truth is the characters in this show don't actually age, so just let us stick with "**th."]
[See you next time.]
(藍染)なぜなら君は 人間と…｡